This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
やっぱり チートだよ
全１のタカノアイも
He must be cheating too.
愛理ちゃん
So much for first place, TAKANO_EYE.
はい 八汐さん
ゲジ姉なのか 何やってたの
Airi!
Yes, Yashio?
実証実験経過を確認中です
Ah, Sister Centipede?
本日 日本標準時西暦２０１９年８月１１日
What're you doing?
I am confirming the results of a substantive experiment.
Today, August 11th, 2019 JST by the western calendar is substantive experiment NO. 2946.
実証実験ナンバー２９４６となります
実験？
ＥＧＩシステムを用いた実験です
ああ あのピーガー音を空に向けて飛ばしてたのか
What experiment?
It uses the EGI system.
それで 何か成果は得られたの
Ah, you broadcasted that signal to the sky again?
はい 今まさに
Did it work?
Yes. Very much so.
石？
Huh? A stone?
何だ これ
あぁ モノポール
モノポールです
What's this?!
A monopole.
…って 何だっけ
Ah, a monopole.
What was that again?
すれ違う　言葉の裏に
閉ざされた　心の鍵
Behind the words passing by
The key of my closed heart is hidden
君という　フラグ解除が
笑顔救えるのなら
If setting your flag
Could save your smile
夏の風いざなう　白昼のスコール
The late summer breeze
波長シンクロ
Turns into a midday squall
ロマンチックみたいに　気の利いた言葉も
As we sync our wavelengths
I'm such a bad romantic
見つからないけど　青空を目指すから
Can't even find
Any words with an edge
Still I aim for the blue sky
僕たちは　一つになれる
戸惑いの涙も　夢も
We can become one
As our dreams and confused tears
真実に　引き寄せられるもの
Draw us ever closer to the truth
それは愛しすぎる
That becomes our beloved
魔法のキーワード
Magical keyword
本字幕由諸神字幕組出品,僅供學習交流之用 更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄 www.kamigami.org
---諸神字幕組---
台本：卷
翻译:臭屁匠 苜汐瞳
校对: mam
后期:Ressul zzz
A robot only we can build
オーバーホールはサービスしてやる
Consider the overhaul my present.
But don't forget that it was you who installed a broken engine without checking first.
ただし 粗悪品をろくに整備せずに載せたのはお前だ
そのことを忘れるな
まだガンつく１にこだわるつもりですか
You're still obsessed with the GunPro-1?
当たり前でしょ 何度も言ったよ
Of course!
Didn't I tell you? I can't give up.
諦めるわけには いかないの
何？ これ
What's this?
Simulation results for the GunPro-1's activation.
ガンつく１が起動した場合のシミュレーション結果です
どうにか方法がないかと色々探ってみました
I tried to find out what possibilities we have.
残念ながら 根本的なところから考え直すしか手はありません
Sadly, it's necessary that we rethink it from the first stages.
この前のようなことを繰り返すだけです
We'd end up repeating failure like the last time otherwise.
From: Yashio
To: My cute junior
Could you come to Space Hill Park?
There's something I want you to check.
八汐先輩？
From Yashio?
モノポール
A monopole?
Yeah.
笑うところですか
Am I supposed to laugh?
じゃあ 触ってみなよ
Try touching it.
ねっ こんな石 見たことないでしょ
I've never seen a stone like this.
確かに 鉱物がこんな放電するなんて聞いたことがありません
Yeah, a rock emitting a magnetic field like that is new.
でも どうしてモノポールと？
But how do you know it's a monopole?
Uh well...
いや それは…
っていうか モノポールって何？
What's a monopole in the first place?
分からないんですか
You don't know?
一応 説明は聞いたんだけど
Well, I heard an explanation, but still...
愛理たん とかいう変なアプリですか
Was it that weird Airi app?
愛理たん…？
Airi? You heard from Frau?
あっ フラウか
ええ うさんくさいですよ
Yeah.
It's suspicious. I'd say you shouldn't trust it much.
あまり信じない方がいいかと思いますが
I'm not trusting it, just...
いや 俺も信じてるわけじゃないんだけど
通常 磁石はたとえ折っても２つの磁石になるだけで
Even if you tried breaking a magnet, it'd just become two magnets.
片方の極だけが存在することはあり得ません
One pole in itself doesn't exist.
Ｎ極かＳ極が単独で存在している それがモノポールです
A monopole is just that:
an independent north or south pole.
理論上存在するとされていますが
Theoretically, they might exist, but none have been found so far.
実在したものはまだ見つかっていません
ここに落ちてたんですか
It was lying here?
More accurately, it fell down here. From the sky.
いや 正確には落ちてきた 空から
愛理の話によると また落ちてくる可能性があるっていうんだけど
Airi says more could be falling later.
No way!
嘘
昴君が呼んだわけ？
You called her, Subaru?
I think I asked you to come alone.
よくないなぁ俺は ２人きりでって言ったのに
仲間になりたそうな目で見てますよ
She had those "I wanna join" puppy eyes.
Are you gonna let her join?
仲間にするんですか
いいえ
No.
寂しそうに去っていきますね
She's leaving with a terribly sad expression.
しょうがないな アキちゃん
I've no choice, huh?
Aki!
何？ 何？
What-what?
もしかして 全部 聞いてた？
You listened to all of it?
Yeah!
それ モノポ…
That's a monop—
そんな大声で しゃべらない
Don't shout!
何すんのよ
What're you doing?! If it's real, then it's a huge discovery!
だって 本物だったら大発見だよ
売ったら 数百… いや 数千万
We could sell it for dozens... no, hundreds of millions!
借金 返して ロボの部品も全部…
We could pay back our debts and finish the robot!
This is a problem on a whole different scale.
そんな次元の問題じゃないですよ
世紀の発見です
This is the discovery of the century.
If it's the real thing, that is.
もっとも 本物だったらの話ですけど
そんなに すごいものなの
Is it such a big deal?
It comes up often in sci-fi.
ＳＦなどで出てきたことがあります
すごいエネルギーを発生させる可能性があるといわれているんです
It's thought to produce tremendous energy.
エネルギーか
Energy...
Monopoles are magnets, right? Then could we use them in engines?
モノポールって磁石でしょ
だったら モーターに使えないかな
まあ 可能性としてゼロではないんですが
Well, I can't deny the possibility,
but we can't do anything with just one of them.
１個では話になりません
ねえ カイ
Hey, Kai!
何？
What?
モノポール降らせて
Make it rain monopoles!
As if I could!
できるわけないでしょ
I'm no rainmaker shaman, you know.
雨乞いの祈とう師じゃないんだから
やっと起きましたね
She woke up.
もう ほっとかないでよ
Don't just let me sleep!
I can concentrate on my game that way.
寝ててもらった方がゲームに集中できるし
部長の相手は面倒なので
It's a pain in the neck to go along with your shenanigans.
２人とも 正直過ぎる
You two are too straightforward!
それで モノポールは？ 幾つ落ちてきた？
How many monopoles have fallen?
まったく
None.
また落ちてくるって 愛理は言ったんでしょ
But Airi said more would fall later? Right, Kai?
ねえ カイ
Sorry, I'm up against TAGIRIN now.
ごめん 今タジリン相手なんだ
邪魔したら たとえアキちゃんでも許さないよ
Not even you are allowed to disturb me right now.
アキちゃん
Aki! Misa always moved to the right after an attack, right?
ミサ姉ってさ 攻撃の後 いつも右回りで逃げてたよね
知らない
How should I know?
そんなことより モノポール
Focus on the monopoles now!
って もう こんな時間？
Wait, it's this late already?
昴 お父さん 平気なの
Subaru, is your dad gonna be okay with this?
別に ホビーロボット造っているわけじゃありませんので
I'm not building hobby robots or anything.
それより ガンつく１の件真面目に考えてもらえませんか
More importantly, could you
seriously reconsider the GunPro-1?
There's no point in being obsessed with a machine you cannot complete.
実現の見込みのない機体にこだわるメリットはまったくありません
But Doc will fix the engine for us!
でも エンジンもドクが直してくれるっていうし
直したからって どうにかなるんですか
So what if he fixes it?
あの重量の機体を２本の脚で何とか支えて動く
You can barely make that heavy machine move on its two legs.
それに 何の意味があるんです？
What's the point in that?
でも ガンつく１は
But the GunPro-1's...
天王寺さんの提案どおり 新たな機体を造るべきです
You should listen to Ms. Tennouji and build a new machine.
そうすれば ＪＡＸＡの支援だって得られるんですよ
Then you could get JAXA's support as well.
でっ…
じゃあ
Bye.
それ 何？
What's that?
Subaru made a simulation of the GunPro-1.
昴が作ってきたガンつく１のシミュレーション
No matter what we did, the current one could never become the robot we imagined.
今のままじゃ どう改造しても
うちらが想像していたロボにはならないって
What are you gonna do?
どうするの
Dunno... Anyway, let's call it a day for now!
そうだねぇ 取りあえず 今日は解散
This is terrible... Just kill me already!
鬱だ
いっそ殺せ 太陽 マジ殺人光線
The Sun's gonna zap me to death!
神代さん せめて 少しは歩こうとして
Koujiro, could you at least try to walk?
Duhuhu!
You smell tera-great, karate girl!
空手先輩 テラいい匂い クンカ クンカ
Sniff-sniff!
Stop that!
ちょっ ちょっとやめてよ
Is this the aroma of vanilla? Too lewd!
この香りバニラですな 色気出しおって このビッチが 爆発しろ
You bitch! Drop dead!
Well, today I want to help you develop your own debate skills,
よーし
今日はお前たちのディベート力を養うために 先生はノータッチを貫く
so I won't be taking part in this meeting!
いいな
Is that what they call an abdication of responsibility?
それって責任放棄？
I'll be taking a sweet nap.
先生は昼寝しているから 瀬乃宮妹 会合の結果を報告するように
Little Senomiya, come to report the good news later!
How irresponsible...
何て無責任な
いいよ 最初から期待してなかったし うちらだけで行こう
It's fine. Not like we expected anything from him in the first place.
Let's go by ourselves!
I see. So you still want to complete No. 1 somehow, right?
そうですか
やはり １号機を何とか完成させたいということですね
はい あれはうちらだけのロボットじゃないんです
Yes. It's not just our work.
It's the fruit of the Robotics Club's long years of work.
ロボ部の思いがこもったロボットですから
Very well.
分かりました そこまで言うなら
If you're that determined, we should look into ways of making it work.
今日はあのロボットをどうにかする方法を もう少し模索してみましょう
ちょっと いいですか
May I?
I prepared a report for today's meeting.
今日の会議用に レジュメを作ってきました
Can I hand it out?
配ってもいいですか
助かります ぜひぜひ
That'd be nice! Please do so!
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1 and suggestions for the future?
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
１号機の失敗の原因と今後についての提案
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
Observations of the GunPro-1's activation test
Regarding the reasons for the failure of No. 1
and suggestions for the future
Hidaka Subaru
I'm sorry for the poor quality...
見づらくて 申し訳ないんですが
It's fine. It looks great to me.
そんなことないです これはとってもいい仕事だと思いますよ
昴君 照れてないで 進めて
Subaru, don't blush. Move on.
にゃっ て… 照れてません
I'm not blushing!
That's surprising. Even Hidaka can get nervous.
意外だな 日高君でも緊張するんだ
Virgin master race. Duhuhu.
童貞 乙
だかりゃ 僕は…
I just...
アキちゃんが読んであげたら？
Aki, how about you read it? Subaru can help if you get stuck.
分からない所は 昴君にフォローしてもらって
Okay then...
じゃあ えーと…
Regarding the failure of No. 1.
１号機の失敗について…
It didn't fail!
って 失敗はしてないけどね
Aki...
アキちゃん
分かってる えーと…
I know.
The biggest reasons were the lack of skill and good equipment.
一番大きな要因は技術力不足と
いい素材を用意できなかったことである か
はい 設計図の出来は決して悪くはなかった
Yes. The plans weren't bad at all.
But due to the lack of funds to realize the plans,
ですが 実際に造るための資金が足りず
parts that weren't considered during the planning were used,
設計段階では想定してなかった素材をあてがい
出力の足りない動力で補おうとし 結果 失敗作となった
and there wasn't enough energy to actually move it, thus, it failed.
It didn't fail! It walked!
だから 失敗作じゃないって ちゃんと歩いたし
失敗作ですよ 動いただけ奇跡です
It failed. It's a miracle that it moved at all.
でも あの重さで動いた とも言えます
But it moved with that weight.
はい それは設計のコンセプトが間違っていなかったという証明でもあります
Yes. That's the proof that the plan concepts aren't wrong.
ですから この経験を生かして 僕は新たな機体を造るべきだと思います
So, based on what we learned from this experience,
I think that we should build a new machine.
Really?
そうなんですか
Subaru...
昴
I told you what I think the other day.
僕の考えは 先日 きちんと話したはずです
では レジュメの次のページから読んでいきます
Let's continue from the next page of the report.
まず ロボットを制作するに当たっちゅ…
First of all, the following are considu—
considered to be necessary for building the robot.
ロボットを制作するに当たって必要な項目
基本構造 素材 電源 モーター 操縦方法 プログラム
Framework. Materials. Energy source. Motors. Control method. Programming.
First, we must at least create a frame more efficient than that of No. 1.
まず 基本構造は
１号機よりパフォーマンスが上回っていることが 最低条件となります
That's natural.
それは当然ですね
Personally, I'd like it if it could move its arms and waist as well.
私としては 可能ならば腕とか腰も動いてほしいです
You know, like the M-45!
ほら Ｍ４５みたいに
Ｍ４５？
The M-45?
あの伝説のチャンプ ミスター・プレアデスのパートナー
The partner of the legendary champion, Mister Pleiades!
私 ファンなんですよね
I'm a huge fan!
It'd be great if we could make a giant robot like that.
あれを大きくしたような巨大ロボができれば 一番なんですが
How many servo motors are there in this hobby robot?
このホビーロボットで サーボモーターは幾つ使ってます？
２４個
24.
That's the first problem.
それが まず 問題です
If we just enlarged it, we'd need to install motors to every joint.
このまま大きくするとなると モーターを関節ごとに入れなくてはならない
重量だけで相当なものです
Just that is quite a significant weight burden.
If we made it 10 times taller, it'd get 1000 times heavier.
単純に高さを１０倍にすると 重さは１，０００倍になるわけですからね
そうなの
Really?
The volume grows cubically.
体積が３乗になりますから
これは ホビーロボットのおおよそ５倍の大きさのロボットです
This robot is about 5 times bigger than that hobby robot.
By using aluminum for the frame and doing everything possible to make it lighter,
素材をアルミにして限界まで軽量化して
it's possible to make it walk like this.
このように歩行することが可能になります
もし これだけの関節を稼働させようと思えば
If you wanted it to move this much, making it lighter would require
素材にダイヤモンド被膜とカーボンファイバーの複合素材を使うなどして
the elements to be made of carbon fiber composites with diamond coating.
軽量化を図る必要があります
That's slightly unrealistic price-wise.
それは ちょっと現実味がないですね お値段的に
そうなると 必然的に外観は こうなります
In that case, it would inevitably end up looking like this.
カッコ悪い
It's so uncool!
１号機だって似たようなもんじゃないですか
No. 1 isn't much better.
あれは 結果的にああなっちゃっただけだもん
It just ended up like that!
If the result is the same, it's the same.
結果が同じなら 同じでしょう
It's not the same!
同じじゃないよ
They aren't getting along well, are they?
あの２人 なかなかうまくいかないね
Our seniors kept building that robot, putting their hearts into each part of it!
これは 良い萌えでつね
That's moe at its best.
こなちゃん 近い
Could you get off me?
Then why didn't you consider making it lighter, or make any plan to actually activate it?
では 部長はなぜ軽量化とか現実に稼働させるプランを…
You could use this for the Gunvarrel look!
これみたいにすれば ガンヴァレルの外観にできるんじゃないかな
Our seniors' heritage is—
ジュン どういうこと
What do you mean, Jun?
You're a maid with cat ears on Yashio's PokeCom.
今 八汐君のポケコンの中で
あき穂ちゃんが猫耳メイドに変わっているんだけど
カイ また？
Kai, again?!
Uh...
いや…
ポケコンの中…
In the PokeCom... So that's AR?
つまり ＡＲということか
それは 確かに 可能かもしれない
That could work.
At the Expo, we could use AR to make it look like Gunvarrel when seen through a PokeCom.
つまり 万博でポケコン越しに見たとき
ＡＲで これがガンヴァレルに見えるようにすればいい
それなら 外観は無視できます
Then we wouldn't have to worry about its looks.
なるほど それで動き回ればポケコンの中では
I see. If you moved it, in the PokeCom it'd look like Gunvarrel moving.
ガンヴァレルが動いているように見える
面白いかもしれませんね
That sounds interesting.
つまり 元気一発…
That means... Lightning speed Genk—
In that case, the controls are left.
だとすると 後は 操縦形態と…
そ… それは『キルバラ』システムで いいんじゃね？
Can't we use the Kill-Ballad system?
確かに それなら早い
That would be the quickest.
ということは 自動的に オペレーターは
That'd mean that the operator would of course be...
待ってよ 俺は…
Wait! I'm—
No. 2 would be remote controlled and use an external electricity source.
２号機は遠隔操作 電源も外部電源を使います
それなら 問題ないでしょう
That's fine, right?
So he won't ride it?
乗らないの
当たり前です 最大の問題は重量なんですから
Of course not. Weight is the biggest problem.
でも
But—
それで造れるかもしれないんですよ
Then we could build a robot we wouldn't be ashamed to show at the Expo.
万博に持っていっても恥ずかしくないロボットが
How did the meeting go?
それで 会議は どうだった
It was fun.
面白かったですよ
We still have many problems ahead though.
まあ まだまだ 前途は多難ですけど
だろうね
That's natural.
They're all unique children, but their team's well-balanced.
個性的な子ばかりですけど バランスはいいんです あのチーム
きっと うまくいきますよ
I'm sure it'll work out.
お姉ちゃん
Sis!
うち ロボ部に入る そしてお姉ちゃんの夢をかなえる
I'll join the Robotics Club and fulfill your dream!
アキは何をやっても平凡止まりなのよ
Whatever you do, it'll always be ordinary.
アキちゃん
Aki!
Kai?
カイ
寝不足は駄目だって言ったはずだよ
You shouldn't neglect sleep.
I want to take the GunPro-1 to the Expo.
うちね ガンつく１で 万博に行きたいの
でもね 昴の言うとおり それはきっと無理
But as Subaru said, it's probably impossible.
そうなの
Really?
この前の実験 見たら うちでも分かるよ
After that last experiment, even I realized it.
新しいものを造らなきゃ駄目だって
We must build it anew.
だから 昴も一生懸命 考えてきてくれたのに
Subaru thought about it so much too...
ねえ カイ
Say, Kai...
カイなら どうする？
What would you do?
What's your dream, Aki?
アキちゃんの夢は万博に行くこと？ ガンつくを完成させること？
To go to the Expo? To finish the GunPro-1?
That's right.
そうだよね
The choice is mine, right?
うちが選ぶしかないよね
お姉ちゃんの言うとおりだけど
You're right, but still!
でも お姉ちゃんの夢はきっとうちがかなえるから
I'll be sure to fulfill your dream!
それまで 東京で待ってて
Wait for me in Tokyo until then!
Koujiro, it's not fair to take it all for yourself!
神代さん 独り占め ずるいよ
ガンつく２？
The GunPro-2?
Yeah. The Gunvarrel Construction Project Test Product 2.
「ガンヴァレルを造ろうプロジェクト試作２号機」 略してガンつく２
In short, GunPro-2.
天王寺さんと昴の提案に乗ってみようかと思って
I think we should go with Ms. Tennouji and Subaru's suggestion.
つまり ガンつく１は諦めると
So you give up on the GunPro-1?
No, I don't.
ううん 諦めない
ガンつく１も 後で ちゃんと造る
I'll finish the GunPro-1 eventually.
でも 万博にはガンつく２を造って持っていく
But we're taking the GunPro-2 to the Expo.
The five of us!
うちら５人で
Five?
５人？
Yeah, us.
うん うちでしょ カイ ジュン フラウ坊
Kai, Jun, Frau Bow, and Subaru.
それに 昴も
別に いいですよ
Whatever.
顔色一つ変えないなんて うちにとっては一大決心だったのに
You could at least pretend to be touched!
It was such a big decision for me!
Listen, Frau Bow, Jun!
フラウ坊もジュンも聞いて
Starting today, the Robotics Club will begin building the GunPro-2!
今日から ロボ部はガンつく２の制作に入ります
コンセプトは 「うちらだからこそ造れるロボを」です
The concept: A Robot Only We Can Build!
今回は ジュンだからこそできることとか
I want to use your talents, Jun and Frau Bow, to build the GunPro-2!
フラウ坊だからこそとか そういうのをきちんと取り込んでいきたい
昴のアイデア カイの操縦技術 全てを結集したロボットを造り上げたい
Subaru's ideas! Kai's control skills!
I want to build a robot that has all of that in it!
だから 全員で ガンつく２を造ろう
So let's build the GunPro-2 together!
よーし いくぞ
Let's do this!
何？ それは
Do what?
見れば分かるでしょ
Can't you tell by looking?
みんな 手を出して
Your hands!
Tane Central Robotics Club power punch! Yoiraiki!
チュウタネロボ部 元気一発 よいら～いき
って… みんな 言ってよ
Come on, guys! Say it!
こんにちは 天気の話 聞きたいですか
Hello! Would you like to know the weather?
You haven't changed at all.
変わってないね
You changed so little it makes me shiver.
あまりに変わってなくて ぞっとしちゃうよ
あしたの鹿児島県 種子島 屋久島地方は 東の風がやや強く晴れでしょう
Tomorrow in the area of Tanegashima and Yakushima in Kagoshima prefecture,
eastern wind will be quite strong, and the weather will be clear.
あんたさ ９年間 ずっとここに縛られてるのかい
Tell me this.
You've been bound here for nine years?
しば？ 愛理にはよく分からないです
Bound? I don't understand.
Say Airi...
ねえ 愛理
Could you just disappear?
消えてくんない？
The blinding light of childhood memories
幼い思い出　眩しい波光に
Turns the scenery of my dream
夢に見た景色は
Into monochrome as it lies forgotten
置き忘れたまま
モノクロになって
And vanishes from my eyes
瞳から消える
But you've always been
だけどいつでも君は
Looking straight at the future
まっすぐ明日を見つめた
And you paid the price in tears
どれくらいの涙と引き換えに
So we turn our hesitation
だから僕らの迷いも
Into strength by the power
強さに変えてくれる
Of our connected hearts
繋がった心が解き放つ
Feel it! These overflowing emotions
不意に溢れ出す思い
For that someone in the sunset
同じに誰かのために
I'll use what little courage I have
この小さな勇気で
And overcome the rage of the wind
風が吹き荒れても
Because I want to protect you
君を守りたくて
Let's grow big!
You dare target the jailbait?
Tune in next week too!